Guide to the Leslie Brown Papers, 1936-2016 and undated RL.11750
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Research/Subject Files, 1936-2010 and undated
  - Governers and AFC (tobacco), undated (Box 3)
  - The Great Negro Fair 1904, undated (Box 3)
  - Greenwood, Jannett, undated (Box 3)
  - Guide to Black Records in the NC State Archives, undated (Box 3)
  - History of Durham, NC, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Industrial Commission on Negro Affairs 1935, undated (Box 3)
  - Internal Migration, undated (Box 3)
  - Iota Phi Lamda Study: Survey on White Collar Occupation and Negro Women, undated (Box 3)
  - JCP [Jim Crow Project] Slide Collection, undated (Box 3)
  - Jim Crow-- Education, HBCUs, 1998 (Box 3)
  - L. Hickok Trip to Durham, undated (Box 3)
  - Lady Knights of King David (Ritual), undated (Box 3)
  - The Last Poets with Bernard Purdie, Delights of the Garden, 1977 (Box Separated PD Run A Box 1, Audio-phonodisc RL11750-PD-0004)
  - Laws, etc., undated (Box 3)
  - League of Women Voters, undated (Box 3)
  - Lincoln Hospital, undated (Box 3)
  - Local 252--Durham twin, undated (Box 3)
  - Long Road to Brown, Long Road Beyond: Race and Public Education in North Carolina, undated (Box 16, Dvd RL11750-DVD-0001)
  - Lott Carey Missionary, undated (Box 3)
  - Louanna Lee Brown, 1945-1990 (Box 17)
  - [Maps of Balck Neighborhoods], undated (Box 10)
  - Mary Church Terrell Papers microfilm, 1976 (Box 4)
  - Master List (OHS Conf.), 1997 (Box 4)
  - McCray, John H. "Letter to Mr. Thurgood Marshall", undated (Box 4)
  - McCristian, Fred, "The South's Negro Teaching Force", undated (Box 4)
  - McGee, Norman L. "The Program of the Young College-bred Negro", undated (Box 4)
  - Mebane, Mary, undated (Box 4)
  - Milestones along the Color Line, undated (Box 4)
  - Military collection, undated (Box 4)
  - Misc. John L. Larkin Papers, undated (Box 4)
  - Mitchell Family Letters, Booker Papers, SOHP-UNC, 1996 (Box 4)
  - [Mobius Union Catalog records], 2006 (Box 4)
  - Moms Mabley project, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Moms Mabley at the "UN", 1960 December (Box Separated PD Run A Box 1, Audio-phonodisc RL11750-PD-0002)
  - Moms Mabley, The Best of, 1971 (Box Separated PD Run A Box 1, Audio-phonodisc RL11750-PD-0003)
  - Monthly Summary of Events and Trends in Race Relations, undated (Box 4)
  - Morehead Baptist Church, undated (Box 4)
  - NAACP Durham, undated (Box 4)
  - NAACP Papers, undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - NAACP Part 12 Selected Branch Files Group I Series Box 6 G147 Durham Branch, undated (Box 4)
  - NAACP Series A part 12 Selected Branch Files 1913-1939, Group I Box 6-146, NC State Conference, undated (Box 4)
  - National Archives info, 1995 (Box 4)
  - National Archives Microfilm F#412, undated (Box 16, Film RL11750-MF-0001)
  - National Archives Microfilm T623-1193, undated (Box 16, Film RL11750-MF-0002)
  - National Archives Microfilm T624-1108, undated (Box 16, Film RL11750-MF-0003)
  - National Archives Microfilm T624-1109, undated (Box 16, Film RL11750-MF-0004)
  - National Archives Microfilm T625-1291, undated (Box 16, Film RL11750-MF-0005)
  - National Archives Microfilm T625-1292, undated (Box 16, Film RL11750-MF-0006)
  - National Archives Microfilm T626-1686, undated (Box 16, Film RL11750-MF-0007)
  - National Archives Microfilm T626-1687, undated (Box 16, Film RL11750-MF-0008)
  - National Archives Microfilm T626-1688, undated (Box 16, Film RL11750-MF-0009)
  - NACWC [National Association of Colored Women Collection] Papers, undated (Box 4)
  - NACW Papers--Selections, undated (Box 4)
  - National Memorial to the Progress of the Colored Race, 1936? (Box 17)
  - National Negro Business League, undated (Box 4)
  - National Negro Congress, undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - National Training School/ Durham State Normal, undated (Box 4)
  - [National Urban League], undated (Box 4)
  - National Youth Organization, undated (Box 4)
  - NC Annual Report/Labor, undated (Box 4)
  - NC Center for Study of Black History, undated (Box 4)
  - NC College/Shepard, undated (Box 4)
  - NC Conference for Social Service, undated (Box 4)
  - NC Congress of Colored Parents and Teachers, undated (Box 4)
  - NC Convention of Freedmen, 1998 (Box 4)
  - NC Council of Defense, 2002 (Box 4)
  - NC Council on Defense, 1996 (Box 4)
  - NC Division of Negro Education, undated (Box 4)
  - NC Equal Suffrage Amendment materials and correspondence, undated (Box 4)
  - NC Federation/Colored Women's Clubs, undated (Box 4)
  - NC Negro Teachers Association minutes, undated (Box 4)
  - NC Public Charities, undated (Box 4)
  - NC Republican Party 1900s, undated (Box 4)
  - NC State Archives, undated (Box 4)
  - NC State Board of Charities and Public Welfare--A Survey of some resources for Negroes, undated (Box 4)
  - NC State Health Dept. 1922 bulletin, undated (Box 4)
  - NC Teachers Assoc. Membership Lists (Durham), undated (Box 4)
  - NCNW {National Council of Negro Women] Durham and NC 1940s, undated (Box 4)
  - NCNW Minutes 1960s, undated (Box 4)
  - Negro Durham Marches On, undated (Box 4)
  - Negro Hospital and Medical Needs NC 1945, undated (Box 4)
  - New Deal Agencies and Black America, undated (Box 4)
  - Newbold, NC, "Conference for Negro Edu. in Raleigh", undated (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Collection, undated (Box 4)
  - North Carolina--Durham County, undated (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Handbook for Women Students 1960-61, undated (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Regulations for Women 1955-56, undated (Box 4)
  - North Carolina Teacher's Record, undated (Box 4)
  - Notes and Black Politics, undated (Box 5)
  - NRA Hearings, Davis--1936 Testimony, undated (Box 5)
  - Overheads, undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Panthers, 1996; undated (Box 5)
  - Papers of NAACP Pt. 11: Special Protests 1912-1939 Series A, Reel 23 of 25, undated (Box 5)
  - Pauli Murray Papers, undated; 8 folders (Box 5)
  - Pauli Murray--Durham, undated (Box 5)
  - Pearson, Minnie, undated (Box 5)
  - Progressive Negroes, undated (Box 5)
  - Proudly They Came... To Honor America, 1970 July 4 (Box Separated PD Run A Box 1, Audio-phonodisc RL11750-PD-0001)
  - Proudly They Came... To Honor America, 1970 July 4 (Box Separated PD Run A Box 1, Audio-phonodisc RL11750-PD-0005)
  - Public Documents, undated (Box 5)
  - Records of the Women's Bureau, undated (Box 5)
  - Reflections on "Behind the Veil" as a Transformative Experience, 2010 October 30 (Box 16, Dvd RL11750-DVD-0003)
  - Registry of Voters 1868, undated (Box 5)
  - [Report and Recommends. to NC Public Schools], undated (Box 5)
  - Report of the Youth Committee Social Planning 1944, undated (Box 5)
  - Research, 1979; undated (Box 5)
  - Robert C. Weaver Papers, undated (Box 5)
  - Rural-Urban Migration, NC, 1920-1930 #235, undated (Box 5)
  - Schools at War Reproductions, 1996 (Box 12)
  - Section on Shepard, undated (Box 5)
  - "Senoirity and the Negro Worker" by Robert C. Weaver, undated (Box 5)
  - Shepard, J.E. "An Appeal", undated (Box 5)
  - Slater Study--Secondary Edu in NC, undated (Box 5)
  - Social Services Directory 1936-1937, undated (Box 5)
  - SOHP [Southern Oral History Program] CR Women, 1978 (Box 5)
  - SOHP interviews, 2002 (Box 5)
  - SOHP Intv--Whites, undated (Box 5)
  - [Sources by or about Af-Ams at Williams and in Berkshire County], 2001 (Box 5)
  - Southeastern Federation of Negro Women's Clubs, undated (Box 5)
  - Southern Commission for the Study of Lynching, undated (Box 5)
  - Southern Unions, undated (Box 5)
  - Southgate Jones, undated (Box 5)
  - Spaulding Papers, undated (Box 5)
  - Spaulding papers Duke Spec. Coll., undated (Box 5)
  - Spicely Murder--Durham, undated (Box 5)
  - St. Joseph's AME Church, undated (Box 5)
  - St. Louis, 2002 (Box 5)
  - St. Louis Circuit Court, 2003 (Box 5)
  - St. Louis--Durham, undated (Box 5)
  - St. Titus Episcopal (Durham), undated (Box 5)
  - Stanford L. Warren Library, undated (Box 5)
  - Stats 1890-1950, undated (Box 5)
  - [Strong Papers Notes], undated (Box 5)
  - Survey of Social Welfare Problems and Agencies, Durham 1941, undated (Box 5)
  - SYNC, undated (Box 5)
  - Tables/Statistics, undated (Box 12)
  - Teacher Qualifications and Salary Guidelines 1922, undated (Box 5)
  - Terkel Intv. w/C.P. Ellis--"American Dreams: Lost and Found" 1980, undated (Box 5)
  - [The Northern Synthesis], undated (Box 10)
  - [The Tobacco Worker in Durham], undated (Box 6)
  - Tobacco People (Durham), undated (Box 6)
  - Tobacco Study--Nat'l Recovery Admin. (1938), undated (Box 6)
  - Tobacco Workers Int'l Union Papers (U. Md.), undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Trice Letters 1940s/50s, undated (Box 6)
  - [UNC Dept of History], 2000 (Box 6)
  - Urban Negro History in NC, undated (Box 6)
  - U.S. News and W/R on 100 yr olds 1995, undated (Box 6)
  - Vann, Andre--"Black Women United" 1917-1953, undated (Box 6)
  - Visual Authorship: Women and Photographs, undated (Box 6)
  - Volkamenia Club meetings--minutes 1947; 1940-46, undated (Box 6)
  - Volkamenia Club--minutes of meetings 1947-48; 61-64, undated (Box 6)
  - Volkamenia Club meetings--minutes 1964, 63, 61, undated (Box 6)
  - [Volkmenia Club Papers], undated (Box 10)
  - Volkamenia Club 1970s-1980s, undated (Box 6)
  - Voting, undated (Box 6)
  - Walker on Conflict, undated (Box 6)
  - War Effort, undated (Box 6)
  - Washington, B.T., Durham NC: A City of Negro Enterprise, undated (Box 6)
  - Weare, Walter, Black Business: Behind the Veil, undated (Box 6)
  - Weaver, Garett, Dev. Bull Durham Community (1880-1915), undated (Box 6)
  - Weaver/Spaulding, Nat'l Ind. Recovery Act, undated (Box 6)
  - Wesley, Charles, History of the Nat'l Assoc. of Colored Women's Clubs, undated (Box 6)
  - Wells-Barnett, Ida B., undated (Box 6)
  - W.G. Pearson, undated (Box 6)
  - [W.K. Parrish papers], 2002 (Box 6)
  - Women in Antebellum St. Louis--Slave/free, 2000-2006 (Box 6)
  - Women United--Sovenir book/ Nat'l Council of Negro Women, undated (Box 6)
  - Women's Baptist Home and Foreign Mission Convention, undated (Box 6)
  - Women's Bureau: Correspondence, undated; 8 folders (Box 6)
  - Women for Action, 1991 (Box 6)
  - Works Progress Administration, undated (Box 6)
  - WPA Real Property Survey, Durham NC 1939-40, undated (Box 6)
  - WPA Records, National Archives, 1995 (Box 6)
  - YWCA, undated (Box 6)
  - YWCA Research, undated (Box 6)
- Course Materials, 1992-2015
  Includes Leslie Brown's subject and course files for teaching, with an emphasis on African-American studies and training in the preparation of oral histories.
  - 1960s and Black Panthers, undated (Box 6)
  - A-A History--Black Power, 1994 (Box 6)
  - Af-Am Hist. Notes, 1992-1999; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Af-Am History, Slavery-American Revolution, 1999 (Box 6)
  - Af-Am History Survey Class 3/4 Slave Trade, Undated (Box 7)
  - African-Americans Women's History/The Last Taboo, Undated (Box 7)
  - African-American History and Law and Authority in 20c. US, 1993-1998 (Box 7)
  - American Paradox-Slavery, Undated (Box 7)
  - Annies' Women's History Courses (materials), Undated (Box 7)
  - Archive Syllabi, 1994-2007; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Associations for the Protection of Negro Women, undated (Box 7)
  - Bibliographies (Af-Am Hist.), 1993-2001 (Box 7)
  - Black Power, Black Panthers, 2005 (Box 7)
  - BPP [Black Panther Party] Programs, etc., 2008 (Box 7)
  - BTV [Behind the Veil] Course, undated (Box 7)
  - [Buy Clothing with this Label], undated (Box 10)
  - Colonial Survey, undated (Box 7)
  - Communism, undated (Box 7)
  - Confederate Flag Issue, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Course Journal, 2015 (Box 7)
  - Course materials, 1997-2008; undated; 878 files, 38 folders, 582 MB (Digital-materials RL11750-SET-0006)
    Word, WordPerfect, Access, GIF, JPEG, Hypertext Markup, GZIP, Windows Metaflle Image, Vector Markup Language, Plain Text, HTML, Adobe, Powerpoint, .wav, .mvr files, includes syllabi, assignments, lecture notes, reading lists, exams, still images, maps, and other African-American and oral history course-related presentation materials.
  - Course materials and academia, 1993-2008; 1706 files, 62 folders, 686 MB (Digital-materials RL11750-SET-0007)
    Word, WordPerfect, Notepad, Rich Text, .jpeg, Powerpoint, Adobe files, includes syllabi, assignments, lecture notes, reading lists, exams, and still images for African-American and oral history courses, along with Brown's curriculum vita, preliminary exams, thesis notes, press releases, paper and conference proposals, and presentations
  - Course materials and correspondence, 1996-1998; undated; 136 files, 3 folders, 858 KB (Digital-materials RL11750-SET-0008)
  - [Course Notes], undated (Box 7)
  - Documentary Photo Aids- African American Experience Photographs, undated; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Douglass, 2000-2001 (Box 7)
  - Education, misc., undated (Box 7)
  - Emancipation, 1993-2001 (Box 7)
  - Essay Prompts, misc., 1994-2007 (Box 7)
  - Evolution of Slavery, 1994; undated (Box 7)
  - Five Hundred Year Timeline, undated (Box 7)
  - Free African-American Women (19th c.), undated (Box 7)
  - Freedom, undated (Box 7)
  - From Slavery to Freedom, undated (Box 7)
  - Generations Timeline, undated (Box 7)
  - The Global Color Line TASP, 2006 (Box 7)
  - Great Migration, 1999 (Box 7)
  - The Great Society, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Handouts for Class, undated (Box 7)
  - Hate Crimes, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Hayden Memo (SNCC), 2013 (Box 7)
  - Historians: Keepers of Time Lecture, 2009 (Box 7)
  - Hist. 145A Hanouts and Study Guides, undated (Box 7)
  - History 145B Class Prep, 1993 (Box 7)
  - Hist 318- Teachers, undated (Box 7)
  - Hist 373 Renaissance/Migration, 1994 (Box 7)
  - History 381, undated (Box 7)
  - History 4951, 2008 (Box 7)
  - Intro to AFRA's History, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Intro to Jim Crow, 1998; undated (Box 7)
  - Intro Seminar Civil Rights Readings-Masters, 1999 (Box 7)
  - JCP [Jim Crow Program] Slide Collection, 1993 (Box 7)
  - JCP Set D and E, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Jim Crow Slides, 1999 (Box 7)
  - Jim Crow, undated (Box 7)
  - L90 AFRAs Civil Rights Misc. Materials, 1994-1999 (Box 7)
  - Laing, James T. "Social Status Among Migrant Negros" (1937-1938), undated (Box 7)
  - Legal Racism and Reparations, 2005 (Box 7)
  - LSU Public Talk, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Lynching, undated (Box 7)
  - Martin Luther King Lectures, undated (Box 7)
  - Misc. Course Syllabi, Williams, 2010-2015 (Box 7)
  - Misc. Course Syllabi, Williams, 2012-2015 (Box 7)
  - Newton, I.G. "Expansion of Negro Suffrage in North Carolina" (1957), undated (Box 7)
  - Notebooks and calendars, 2002-2014 and undated; 7 folders (Box 17)
  - Oral History Class, 1995 (Box 7)
  - Oral History Class, 2004 (Box 7)
  - Oral History Theory and Practice, undated (Box 7)
  - Oral History Workshop, 2003 (Box 17)
  - Oral History Workshop, Giles Co., TN, 1994 (Box 17)
  - Outcomes of Civil Rights Mvmt., 2004 (Box 7)
  - Postcards, undated (Box 7)
  - Ralston, Andrew "What Racial Equality Means to the Negro" (1923-1924), undated (Box 7)
  - Reading Monographs, undated (Box 7)
  - Slave Trade Lectures, 1994 (Box 7)
  - Slave Trade Overheads, undated (Box 14)
  - SLPS [St Louis Project Schools] Am. Hist Project, 2006 (Box 8)
  - SNCC- Panthers, 1994 (Box 8)
  - St Louis Public Schools, 2011 (Box 8)
  - Types of Tenancy, undated (Box 8)
  - The Global Color Line, 2006 (Box 8)
  - Untangling the Threads of Sisterhood, 2014 (Box 17)
  - W.E.B. Du Bois "Behold the Land" (1946), undated (Box 8)
  - Women's Studies Courses, 1997 (Box 8)
  - WWI Notes, undated (Box 8)
- Academia, 1975-2016 and undated
  Includes files related to Leslie Brown's conference attendance, her time as a doctoral candidate (there is a copy of her master's thesis, but not her doctoral thesis), job talks and lectures, tenure files, membership in professional organizations, and book projects.
  - Academia, 1992-2015; undated; 5616 files, 226 folders, 4.25 GB (Digital-materials RL11750-SET-0005)
    Word, WordPerfect, Adobe Acrobat, Rich Text, Powerpoint, .wav, .tif, .jpeg files; Projects (especially the teachers domain video review project), presentations, papers, book reviews, journal entries, applications for fellowships and grants, academic works by others, conference materials, curriculum vita, sound files, and still images
  - Afircan American History [Prelim Reading Lists], 1993-2006 (Box 8)
  - AHA, 2006-2007 (Box 8)
  - [American Linguistic Heritage Survey], 2005 (Box 8)
  - American RadioWorks: An Imperfect Revolution, Voices from the Desegregation Era (Box 16, Audio-cd RL.11750-CD-0001)
    by Kate Ellis and Catherine Winter
  - American Women's History {Prelim Reading Lists], 1993 (Box 8)
  - ASA, 2005 November (Box 8)
  - Awards, 1975-2009 and undated (Box 17)
  - B and N/IHF/Af-Am History, 2002 (Box 8)
  - "Behind the Veil: Documenting African American Life in the Jim Crow South" WTVD News Broadcast, 1993 July (Box 16, Videotape RL11750-VHS-0002)
  - [Behind the Veil Invitation], 2016 (Box 8)
  - Behind the Veil [related projects], 1996-2005 (Box 17)
  - Perks Roundtable- Politics od Documentation, 1996 (Box 8)
  - Beloved Project, undated (Box 8)
  - Black Berkshires, 2010 (Box 8)
  - Blackside Symposium, 2005 (Box 8)
  - Book Talk, undated (Box 8)
  - Book UNC Press, 2004-2008 (Box 8)
  - Carnegie Mellon Book Talk, 2010 (Box 8)
  - Center for Documentary Studies, 1991 (Box 8)
  - Chisholm Project, 2004 (Box 8)
  - Christine Strudwick, undated (Box 8)
  - Civil Rights OAH Proposal, 2001-2002 (Box 8)
  - Closing Comments, undated (Box 8)
  - CMU, undated (Box 8)
  - [Correspondence and Photos], 2007 (Box 8)
  - Course materials and academia, 1993-2008; 1706 files, 62 folders, 686 MB (Digital-materials RL11750-SET-0007)
  - [Course Notes], 2011 (Box 8)
  - Craven Comm. College, 2016 (Box 8)
  - Corbett and Miller Article, 2006 (Box 8)
  - Darling Change Lecture, 2013 April (Box 8)
  - Davidson [Talk], 2013 October 6-9 (Box 8)
  - Defence Stuff, 1997 (Box 8)
  - [Disertation Proposal], undated (Box 8)
  - Doctoral ceremony programs, 1998 (Box 17)
  - Duke 50th, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Duke Grad History Association 1990, undated (Box 8)
  - Duke Speech, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Duke University, 1991-1992 (Box 8)
  - Durham/Chapel Hill, 2010 November 2-4 (Box 8)
  - [Durham Photos], 1994 (Box 14)
  - Durham Project Account, 1994-2002; 5 folders (Box 8)
  - ENCY Great Mgiration, 2009 (Box 8)
  - Exploring America Summer Seminar, 2006 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Retreat, 2016 (Box 8)
  - For Leslie- Personal notes, 2016; undated (Box 8)
  - [Freedom Bags: African-American Women and Migration], 2006 (Box 8)
  - Grace and Marjorie Wiggins, 1991-1996 and undated (Box 17)
  - [Hampton Project], 2004 (Box 8)
  - Harvard- NEH Civil Rights Institute, 2000 (Box 14)
  - History Colloquium, 2005 (Box 8)
  - [Interpreting Af-Am History], undated (Box 8)
  - Jim Crow Proposal- Short Introduction, undated (Box 8)
  - [Jim Crow Speech], undated (Box 8)
  - Job Talk UMSL, undated (Box 8)
  - Job Talk WashU, 1999 (Box 8)
  - K-C Talk, 2012 (Box 8)
  - Krieger article--permissions, 2001-2003 (Box 17)
  - LB and AV, St Helena, SC and Tuskeegee, AL, 1994 (Box 14)
  - LB Applications, undated (Box 8)
  - LB-CRM Institute Harvard, 2000 (Box 14)
  - LB Talk on Durham, undated (Box 8)
  - [Left of Black], 2011 (Box 8)
  - Leslie Brown dissertation, 1997; undated; 139 files, 11 folders, 7.55 MB (Digital-materials RL11750-SET-0002)
    WordPerfect and Libre Office files, dissertation chapters, notes, drafts, and final copies. Some file formats may not be supported.
  - Let Freedom Ring, 2011 (Box 8)
  - Letters, addresses, 1990-1995 (Box 17)
  - Liberty and Justice for All Summer Institute, 2005 (Box 8)
  - Living with Jim Crow Lecture, undated (Box 8)
  - Living with Jim Crow program, 2016 (Box 17)
  - Lycoming College, 2015 February 17 (Box 8)
  - [M.A. Thesis], 1991 (Box 8)
  - Main St. Set 2, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Main St. Set 3, 1993 (Box 14)
  - March on Washington, undated (Box 8)
  - MCLA-NEH, June (Box 8)
  - Meeting notes, undated (Box 8)
  - Mentoring Award, 2011 (Box 9)
  - MLK Talk, 2006 (Box 9)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 14)
  - NEH Application, 2000 (Box 9)
  - NEH Grant, 2001-2003 (Box 9)
  - NEH Harvard Application, 2000 (Box 9)
  - NEH Workshop, Durham, NC, 2016 (Box 9)
  - NYC, 2014 (Box 9)
  - OAH, 2007-2009 (Box 9)
  - OATT, 2007 (Box 9)
  - OHA Denver, 2011 (Box 9)
  - OAH Teaching Workshop, 2013 (Box 9)
  - Palgrave O.H. Series, 2006-2011 (Box 17)
  - [Personal Calendar and Notes], 2014-2015 (Box 9)
  - [Personal Notes], 2013 (Box 9)
  - Photographs and slide, 1994-1998 (Box 17)
  - Pins, undated; 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Plenty of Opposition, 2003 (Box 9)
  - Prelim Exams- LB- Fall 1993 (Box 9)
  - Prelim Reading List, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Proposals, 2004 (Box 17)
  - Reader Report, undated (Box 9)
  - Remarks on "Behind the Veil Conference", 1991 (Box 9)
  - Research- Migration, undated (Box 9)
  - Richard Wright: Black Boy, undated (Box 9)
  - Segregated Lives Book Proposal, 2007 (Box 9)
  - Segregated Lines Proposal, 2008 (Box 9)
  - Senate Presentation, 2002 (Box 9)
  - Sernett, Bound for the Promised Land (Review), 1998 (Box 9)
  - Short paper--Dad, 1993 (Box 17)
  - Sisters and Mothers, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Slavery in Missouri, 2000 (Box 9)
  - SLPS, 2011 (Box 9)
  - SLWE- NEH, 2011 (Box 9)
  - St Louis Oral History Project, undated (Box 9)
  - St. Louis Rally Against Racism, 2000 March 31-April 1 (Box 16, Videotape RL11750-VHS-0001)
  - St. Mike's Lecture, 2013 (Box 9)
  - Talk- Black Power in the Civil Rights Era, undated (Box 9)
  - Teaching Am. History Project, 2010 (Box 9)
  - Tenure Files, 1999-2007; 10 folders (Box 9)
  - Things They Tell Us in the Night, BTU Brown Bag, undated (Box 9)
  - To Reach Across a Great Divide, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Travel, 2008 (Box 9)
  - Voices of Af-Am History Collection Talk, undated (Box 9)
  - UMSL, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Univ. of S. Florida, 2015 (Box 9)
  - U of Tenn. Publication, 1999-2002; 5 folders (Box 9)
  - Untitled, 1993 (Box 14)
  - Untitled, undated (Box 14)
  - U.S. Women's History review, 2016 (Box 17)
  - Upbuilding Black Durham, 2011 (Box 9)
  - Washington University, 2007 (Box 9)
  - Washington University- Leslie, 1998-2007 (Box 9)
  - Wiley, Blackwell Contract, 2009 (Box 9)
  - Williams Talk, 2010 (Box 9)
  - Williams WCMA Fellows [Talk], 2013 November 2 (Box 9)
  - Women and Migration Proposal, 2015 (Box 9)
  - Women and Migration Summer 2014 (Box 9)
  - Women are not chicks poster and unidentified photograph, undated (Oversize-folder 1)
- Publications, 1991-2014 and undated
  Printed materials related to African-American history. Topics include African Americans in the resort community at Saratoga Springs, documenting struggle and resistance through oral histories, communism and race, Black recording artists of the 1920s, the civil rights movement, African-American students at Duke University, the Jim Crow era, race relations, race and the United States government, and segregation. Popular magazines feature material on Michelle and Barack Obama, Thomas Jefferson and Sally Hemings, reparations, racism, and college graduation rates.
  - A Walk to Freedom, 1998 (Box 12)
  - A-G, undated (Box 11)
  - African-American Women in Defense of Ourselves, 1991 (Box 12)
  - [Free at Last], undated (Box 11)
  - The Freedom Business, 2006 (Box 17)
  - L-M, undated (Box 11)
  - Publications, 1996-2008; undated; 2121 files, 265 folders, 883 MB (Digital-materials RL11750-SET-0003)
    WordPerftect, Word files; book proposal; article; Discord Behind the Veil draft, manuscript, and photographs; Common Spaces, Separate Lives manuscript draft
  - R-W, undated (Box 11)
  - Slavery and Justice, 2007 (Box 17)
  - Survey Graphic, 1947 Jan., undated (Box 11)
  - Rise and Fall of Jim Crow Discussion Guide, undated (Box 11)
  - Popular Magazines A-N, 2009-2014 (Box 11)
  - Popular Magazines T-V, 1998; 2009 (Box 11)